Roberto Manzella

London, GB robertomanzella.com info@robertomanzella.com +44 (0) 7707797695

I've been playing with computers for a long time! :-)

Based in London... love NodeJS/React/GraphQL/Docker/Git/Serverless!

In the past years I've worked for different companies, from startups to leading global technology companies.

I always push myself to improve the code quality and the working flow everywhere I go. Automation is very important for me, and I always try to speed up and automate as much stuff as I can, from testing tools, continuous delivery, utility tools, etc... to make other devs' lives easier and more relaxed. Trying to use serverless architecture (from different provider like AWS, Google, Azure) as much as I can.

I'm also an enthusiast photographer.

Experience

NowTV - Sky (2016 — Present)

Senior Full Stack Developer, consultant

- Internal CMS for editors to curate the NowTV Devices Homepage
- NodeJS, Mongo, Redis app to feed all the NowTV apps and devices
- Account broadband/tv status page
- Sales website for UK

NodeJS, Docker, React, Redux, React Native, AngularJS, ExpressJS, Jenkins, Mongo, Redis, AWS, Kubernetes

• Photobox (2015 - 2015)

Senior NodeJS Developer, consultant

- NodeJS checkout (payment flow)
- Scaling application for peak season

NodeJS, Docker, AWS, ExpressJS

DigitasLBi (2014 — 2015)

Lead Front End Developer

 World wide platform for Renault, Nissan, Infiniti, Datsun and Dacia. I worked as a Lead FE, leading a team of 10 people and managing offshore resources from Vietnam, Costa Rica, France and Colombia. This team was part of a 200 people group. A huge platform based on Adobe AEM.

Education

University of Palermo (2005 — 2007)

Computer Science

Degree not completed

University of Palermo (2002 — 2004)

Electrical Engineering

Languages

Italian: Native English: Fluent

Interests

Sports Photography New technologies Motorbikes

Various internal projects

React, Backbone, AngularJS, ElasticSearch, NodeJS, Docker, Mongo, Redis

OutOfView Ltd (2012 — 2014)

Lead Front End Developer

- Gliff App (IOS, Android). Not on the Stores anymore. It was supposed to be a viral social app using Memes generated on the app using Canvas
- Quib.ly: A Questions and Answers portal (a la Stack Overflow or Quora) for tech savvy parents and kids (not online anymore)
- Other minor projects (nexus-club.com, mindthegap.org.uk, thegliff.com, altanawealth.com, etc...)

Elasticsearch, NodeJS, Git, Python, Pyramid, AngularJS, Cordova, Ionic

• Giglio.com (2010 - 2012)

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Frontend/Backend for the blogs and the e-commerce website
- DevOps

PHP, Wordpress, Magento, Apache, Nginx, Varnish

• Freelancer (2000 - 2009)

UI designer/Frontend/Backend Developer

 $\bullet \quad \text{Wordpress specialist, templating, etc...} \\$

PHP, Wordpress, Joomla, Magento, Apache, Nginx

Degree not completed

Garibaldi High School of Palermo (1997 — 2002)

Classical Lyceum

High School Diploma